DenysPotapov

senior python developer

contact

+38 050 330-20-57 in denyspotapov denys.potapov@gmail.com

python skills

OpenCV, numpy, pandas, pytest, Django

cloud expirience

GCP, AWS, basic Azure

other skills

basic Jenkins, php, go

languages

bilingual Ukrainian/Russian intermediate English basic German

profile

I am a developer with over 12 years experience working on a variety of projects from conception to delivery. I am confident in a wide range of technologies, now focused on data processing with python. My approach is methodical but creative. I am comfortable working either independently or as part of a team.

education

2002–2008 M.Sc. degree in Computer Science

Specialization in computer systems and robotics

NTUU 'KPI'

experience

2021-present	Virtasant Virtasant developing a SaaS solution to otimize cloud clients. I'm a part of team of 3 person to port the exisit AWS to support new clouds (currently GCP, Axure in fut	ng solution for
2018—2021	freelancer Top Rated freelancer at Upwork.com. Profile link. Suce more than 60 projects in various tech (mainly python, but embedded C). Most of projects were data processing worlding video and image processing.	ut also JS, PHP,
2012—2015	barzo.com.ua Creating and launching a start-up company. Develo ground e-commerce platform (PHP, MySql, HTML, SCSS) and managing team of 3 freelancers.	
2012—2018	Qport Creating a large network of digital signage systems (bigge 8000 screens). Integrating ERP system in retail stores (15	
2009—2012	Qport Developing interactive screens software (python). Deve system for retail stores (1c ERP).	developer eloping an ERP
2008—2009	Physics-technological institute Development and integration of foundry process mo (Object Pascal) for perspective developments departmentals and alloys of the National academy of science of	ent institute of
2005—2007	Proling Office Development of machine translation system ProlingOffice online version (ASP.NET)	developer ce (C#) and it's

awards

June 2016 **Ukraine Dev Challenge** 3rd place

JS Front-end developer

November 2015 **EU Web Challenge** 1st place

Back end development

Codingame oDesk Contest 5th place

python developers

skills

advanced **Python**

Data processing with pandas, numpy;Image and video processing with OpenCV;

Unit and integration testing;

• Full stack web apps with Django.

intermediate front end development

JavaScript, AngularJs, HTML, CSS (SCSS)

basic **php, go, c++**

languages

native Russian/Ukrainian

intermediate **English** conversationally fluent

basic German basic words and phrases only

community

blogging habrahabr.ru

Top-100 author in biggest Russian-speaking IT community

speaking IT conferences

Taking part in local IT conferences as visor and speaker. ('Object Calis-

thenics in php' at WebCamp Developer Day on youtube).

open source PHP password generator library

Library has 24 stars on github and more then 30 download on packagist

interests

volunteer Running a code club

Code-club in Kyiv is a part of network of volunteer-led after school cod-

ing clubs for children aged 9-11

running